Kris Wilson

krispykrisp12@gmail.com | 267-312-8351 | Philadelphia, PA

www.linkedin.com/in/kris-wilson-web-developer | https://github.com/krispykrisp12 | https://krispykrisp12.github.io/My-Portfolio

SUMMARY

Lifelong seeker of knowledge and Penn LPS coding bootcamp graduate who currently has his sights set on a full-time web development position. Self motivated developer who is always researching new things. Experienced in:

- Front End: HTML, CSS, JS, AJAX, React JS, Bootstrap, Handlebars JS, Jquery
- Backend: Node JS, Express, PHP
- **Databases:** MongoDB, MySQL, Firebase, Sequelize
- Version Control: Git

PROJECTS

SuperHero and Villains

UI/UX Developer

Look up superheroes and villains, chat with other comic book fans

- Connected to a comic book API to grab superheroes and villains that is entered into a search bar and display information about them on screen
- Connected to the YouTube API to add a video feature to the site
- When character content is displayed on screen: a button will pop up that will hit the youtube API of that specific character for an exact search inside of a modal

City Sitters https://ancient-badlands-85489.herokuapp.com/

UI/UX Developer

Create a job listing for a babysitter or apply for a sitter job

- Creating the layout of the pages using CSS and Bootstrap
- Found and implemented the images used for the background

EXPERIENCE

Washington College

Course Mentor (Basic of Computing)

9/2009-5/2011

- Recognized for proven ability of understanding the course work
- Good interpersonal and communication skills

Washington College (Theta Chi)

9/2009-5/2011

Webmaster

• Edited and updated the Theta Chi website using dreamweaver

EDUCATION

University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA

5/2018-11/2018

Penn LPS, Full Stack Web Development Boot Camp

An intensive 24-week long boot camp dedicated to designing and building web applications. Skills learned consisted of HTML,, CSS, JS, Jquery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node JS, MySQL, Sequelize, MongoDB, Express, Handlebars JS, & React JS.